bafta.org 2014-10-08

# BAFTA Privacy

### THE BRITISH ACADEMY OF FILM AND TELEVISION ARTS 

PRIVACY POLICY

Welcome to The British Academy of Film and Television Arts. The British Academy of Film and Television Arts and BAFTA Management Limited (jointly referred to as "BAFTA") takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy and cookie policy.

#### ONLINE PRIVACY PRACTICES

1\. We at BAFTA and our affiliated companies ("we, us, our") are keen to strike a fair balance between your personal privacy and ensuring you obtain full value from the internet and other products and services we may be able to offer to you. 

2\. We request that all users read and accept the terms and conditions and this privacy policy. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions or the privacy policy applicable to this Site you must cease using the Site, or the one linked from it that is within our control, immediately.

3\. We are fully registered under the Data Protection Act 1998 ("the Act") and to ensure we comply with all protection the Act affords to you we have set out below how we intend to utilise the information provided by you if you register via the Site homepage or Members' Area. Further information on the Act is on the internet at [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/) .

4\. We will not share your personal information for marketing or any other purposes without your consent unless where required by law. If you have registered your interest with bafta.org and/or any of our associated companies, and thereby given your consent, you may be contacted with relevant promotions, offers or information that you have expressed an interest in or that might be of interest to you. IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO RECEIVE FURTHER UPDATES PLEASE EMAIL [web@bafta.org](mailto:website@bafta.org) . We will always respect your privacy and any personal communication between you and ourselves. We will always comply with any data protection legislation currently in force.

5\. When you access the site, we may ask you to give us your name, email address and other personal information that will be needed to supply the services to you. You can 'unsubscribe' at any time. We may use your personal data for contacting you via the phone or e-mail for support, notification of new products or new versions, general correspondence regarding the Site and correspondence which may relate to you. If you would rather not receive future marketing emails from us once you have registered please inform us by e-mail.

6\. The information you provide will be kept confidential and will only be passed on to external companies if you have opted in to permit BAFTA to give your contact information to selected companies, business partners, sponsors and advertisers. If you opt out of permitting BAFTA to pass on your information, it will be used only to support your customer relationship with us (i.e. e-mails only from BAFTA) and to provide the specified service. We do not disclose or sell your information outside our corporate group except if we sell the whole or part of our business.

7\. Our Site may not always be available and the material on it may not necessarily reflect our views. All users must agree not to tamper with the site and respect our intellectual property rights and those of our licensors and by accepting this privacy policy and the terms and conditions you hereby agree to do so. The Site may also have links to other websites over which we have no control.

8\. In accordance with statutory obligations we only collect personal information from you which is necessary for us to supply the services to you. You have the option at any time to request that we:

  * 8.1 remove details from our database;

  * 8.2 update the information we hold about you or your child;

  * 8.3 request a copy of the information that we hold subject to the payment of a request fee; or

  * 8.4 stop receiving data. 

9\. All you need to do is write to the address below quoting "BAFTA Website" and in each case quote your name and leave a telephone number so that we may contact you. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity.

#### TRADING FROM OUR SITE

10\. Making sure you can buy safely online is a priority for us and certain links accessible from our Site offer items and services online. We have made strenuous efforts to ensure that security is one of our highest priorities and we have devoted a great deal of effort to ensure that our online security measures help to safeguard your information. Where possible we use industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (Verisign) technology to allow for the encryption of:

  * 10.1 potentially sensitive information such as your name and address; and critically-sensitive information like your credit card number. 

  * 10.2 We hope that once you understand the measures we take to help ensure secure transactions and privacy, and the steps you can take yourself, you will be as happy about the safety of your online transaction and order information as we are.

#### COOKIES  

11\. A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that the website can remember who you are. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. Two types of cookies are used on this website:

  * 11.1 Session Cookies: which are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site.

  * 11.2 Persistent cookies: which remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie). 

  * 11.3 Cookies can help a website to arrange content to match your preferred interests more quickly. Most major websites use cookies. Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you. 

#### HOW WE USE COOKIES ON OUR SITE AND WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT

12\. Session Cookies 

  * 12.1 To allow you to carry information across pages of our site and avoid having to re-enter information.

  * 12.2 To allow you to maintain a shopping basket. 

  * 12.3 Within registration to allow you to access stored information. 

13\. Persistent Cookies 

  * 13.1 To help us recognise you as a unique visitor (just a number) when you return to our website and to allow us to tailor content or advertisements to match your preferred interests or to avoid showing you the same adverts repeatedly.

  * 13.2 To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our site and to help us improve the structure of our website. We cannot identify you personally in this way.

  * 13.3 Within research surveys to ensure you are not invited to complete a questionnaire too often or after you have already done so.

#### DISABLING/ENABLING COOKIES  

14\. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of our site if cookies are disabled. Find out how to disable/enable cookies by clicking on the "Manage Cookies" section of the [Interactive Advertising Bureau UK website](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) . 

#### FURTHER INFORMATION ON DATA PROTECTION AND PERSONAL PRIVACY  

15\. For further information from us on data protection and privacy contact us via post sent to the following address: 

**BAFTA Management Limited**  
195 Piccadilly  
London, W1J 9LN 

Information on the Data Protection Act 1998 is also on the Information Commissioner's web site at [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/) . 

BAFTA Management Limited is a company registered in England. Registered number 01163351

#### More Information

  * View our Accessibility Standards
  * View our Terms of Use

## Cookies explained further

### What is a cookie?

Cookies are small text files that are sent by websites that you visit to recognise who you are when you return there. There files are stored on your computer’s hard drive, and are read by your web browser.  
How are cookie used?

Cookies perform several functions, such as remembering who you are on a particular site (your welcome message), to keeping you logged in to your account screen on an ecommerce site (however, you should always log out if you are using a public computer). Advertising agencies also use cookies to find out if they have served you an advert from a particular brand on a site, or if you have seen a particular advert before. Website owners will use cookies to follow which pages that you’ve read so that they can see what parts of the site are popular or not. In short, cookies are a way of providing statistics on site visits as well as some limited functionality that makes your site visit easier. When used properly cookies are an asset to a site visitor and a site owner. They are not viruses, but some unscrupulous outfits will use them maliciously – we follow best practice for cookie use.

A list of all the cookies used on this website by us, and our technology partners can be found in our cookies list .

### Flash cookies?

Adobe uses a particular type of cookie called a ‘Local Shared Object’, which is typically collected if you watch a video for example that uses the Adobe Flash media player, i.e. an embedded YouTube video on a page that is being played via Flash. Please note that these types of cookie will not be found on iPads, which do not support Flash.   
Have a look at Adobe's website if you want to control Flash cookies on your computer. If you’ve got a Firefox browser you can also get an add-on to detect and delete Flash cookies.

### Opting out of cookies?

There are a number of options available so that you do not have to store any cookies at all. You can either set your browser so that it will not accept and store any cookie, or if you have a little more time and knowledge you are able to allow only certain ‘trusted’ sites to store cookies on your computer. These sites may include us (of course!), or the site where you carry out your online banking, or possibly your favourite news service.

It’s worth bearing in mind that if you decide to delete all of your cookies, then you will likely have to re-enter all of your usernames and passwords on all of the sites that you visit, which you previously didn’t even have to think about. As we mentioned before, cookies can be a real asset to your web surfing experience.

The Information Commissioner’s Office ( http://www.ico.gov.uk/ ) provides some advice about cookies and their use, but it also provides a link to ‘About cookies’ ( www.aboutcookies.org ) which is run by the law firm Pinsent Masons. This website provides even more information about cookies if you feel that this page and the ICO is not enough information for you, but it also details how you might delete any cookies that you find, and it also shows you how to allow those trusted sites to store their cookies on your computer.

### What is a web beacon?

Web beacons are also sometimes referred to as ‘web bugs’ and are small single pixel transparent image files. They allow website owners to know when a visitor has reached their website, and are used in conjunction with cookies to allow further website tracking to be monitored. Again, these files are not viruses, but are useful in helping us to make your web surfing experience better.

### Our main technology partners

We work with the following companies in maintaining and improving our website, and they must all satisfy the data protection requirements. If you have any more questions, please do contact us and we’ll be happy to help.

### the OTHER media Limited

the OTHER media provide build and hosting services to BAFTA and help us to maintain the software that runs our website. They provide us with reporting statistics where required, and will serve cookies on our behalf to enable any site personalisation and log in functionality.
